[upbeat techno music plays]
♪♪
[lid creaks]
-[Zooble]: [groans]
Is the adventure over already?
-No -- the adventure hasn't
even started yet.
-[Zooble]: Oh, well,
don't be a narc.
Find your own hiding spot.
-It's not that.
It's just that we haven't
even seen Caine at all today.
Plus, Gangle was
looking for you.
-Hi, Zooble.
-Wait.
What's this?
-[Caine]: Hello, my little
rubber baby buggy bumpers!
Today, I've decided
to go to the store
to get essential ingredients
for my signature
milk and cigarette casserole!
I hope you can handle yourselves
until I get back.
-[Zooble]: Well, this was fun
while it lasted.
-So, uh, what's
the adventure today?
-Oh, I don't have
an adventure for you today.
So you can do
whatever you feel like.
-[Zooble]: All right,
sounds fine to me.
-You should ask me for suggestions
on what to do instead.
-[Zooble]: No.
-What should we do instead?
-[Zooble]: No, Gangle --
-Oh, wait, sorry --
-Great question, Gangle.
For an answer,
let me consult...
the Chinese room!
-[Zooble]: Okay,
he had a bit prepared.
[whimsical music plays]
♪♪
-[Zooble]: Okay, why Chinese?
Does this actually
mean anything?
-It's a mystery
what's behind that door.
But I believe
it's a fluent Chinese speaker
who will give me advice.
-[Zooble]: Can I just ask why?
Like, what even is --
-SHUT!
You're only making
the joke take longer.
♪♪
[laughs manically]
-[Zooble]: [sighs]
What does it say?
-I don't know.
I don't understand Chinese.
-[Kinger]: [chuckles]
-[Zooble]: Hilarious.
-I don't know, why don't you guys
hang out at the digital lake?
These locations have just kinda
been there this whole time.
Not sure why
you never visit them.
-You should throw
a ffffffffffffffffffffffffffff...
freaking beach party.
-Good boy.
-Oh, that could fun.
-Plus there are some
fun NPCs out there
that none of you have
even interacted with yet.
-[Zooble]: I'm guessing
they're not intelligent ones?
-They most certainly are not.
Now, go have fun!
[tropical music plays]
-Wow, what a good day!
Wow!
♪♪
-[Zooble]: All right,
so, who wants to try
Caine's magical
changing booth first?
-I guess I'll give it a go?
[BOINK!] [BONK!]
[POINK!] [DOINK!]
-Wow, you look mediocre!
If you ever need a sunburn,
give me a call!
-I-I don't want a sunburn.
-Should have thought of that
before I decided I hate you!
-Yeah, don't interact
with the sun.
She's just like that.
♪♪
-[Zooble]: Gangle, wait.
[SPLAT!]
♪♪
-Oh!
My eye!
-I'll get it.
♪♪
-Hey, there.
If you want to find
my sunken treasure chest,
you'll have to try
better than that.
[gasps]
So, I was just talking
with my brother here, and yeah --
you are definitely not getting
our sunken treasure chest.
Definitely not.
-[burbled] Do I even want
your treasure chest?
It's not like there's anything
to spend money on.
-[bizarre raspy voice]
I'm the one that tells lies.
-Dude, you ruined it.
-Is that your treasure?
-Duuuude, no!
They took everything!
That was my entire
life savings, dude!
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God,
I'm gonna be sick.
That was everything.
Oh, my God!
-Did you find it?
-Nah.
Somebody plundered it
before I could.
-What?
Oh, wait.
Your eye!
-[sighs]
What was that for?
-[Zooble]: Oh, let me think.
There's that time you ran me over
with a steam roller.
The time you pushed Gangle
into a pool of piranhas.
When you set me on fire,
mailed me a pipe bomb,
threw me into
an active volcano.
I could go on.
-[sighs]
Aren't you supposed to be
miserable about your ability
to choose your own body,
or something?
-[Zooble]: Aren't you supposed to be
causing trouble for everyone?
I've been starting to think that
maybe the ability to change is fine.
Not needing to commit
to one thing all the time.
-How about that.
-[Zooble]: And if I DO
still have problems,
I talk about them
with the people I trust.
-[sighs] Good thing I don't
have any problems, then.
-[Zooble]: Where are you going?
-Anywhere you losers
won't yap my ear off.
-Hello, there!
As the shrimp NPC...
[sizzling]
-You're welcome!
[footsteps approaching]
[eerie scuttling]
[sinister music plays]
♪♪
[pleasant, peaceful music plays]
[doorbell rings]
-[gasps]
[panting]
[door latch clicks]
[sighs]
Way to interrupt my nap.
-Can we talk?
-You're what?
-Yeah.
He's not actually an NPC.
He's a human.
Like us.
-[NPC]: Yes, I know.
[laughs ruefully]
Getting stuck with a blank
mannequin body of all things.
Caine completely overlooked me.
But because of this,
I was able to, uh --
Well...
I think I've found
the way to leave.
-"The way to leave"?
-Yes.
The way to leave the circus
and get back to the real world.
-[NPC]: Shhh!
Yes.
But, please, keep it discreet.
If Caine catches on,
I doubt he'll ever let us
get this far again.
-That's why we came to you.
We thought you might have a key
to the Chinese room.
-The Chinese room?
-[NPC]: Yes.
We're gonna need a place to talk
without Caine listening in on us.
I have a working theory that Caine
will commit to a bit, no matter what.
And if the bit is to not know
what's in the Chinese room,
he'll stick to it.
-Uh, I guess I'll check.
[door creaks]
These are all the keys I have
where I don't know what they go to.
-Wait.
Don't you want
to come with us?
This could be our one chance
to finally leave all this behind.
-[sighs] Sure.
Why not?
-[Zooble]: Where even is Caine?
He might be suspicious
of us even being here.
-[NPC]: He's probably in his office
planning adventures.
-[sighs] How do we even know
we can trust this guy?
Has he done anything
to prove he's human?
-[NPC]: I've been here
longer than any of you.
I, uh...
helped create this place.
I'll explain more
when we're in the room,
but, for now,
please just trust me.
You will not regret it.
[keys jingling]
[curious music plays]
♪♪
-Am I doing this wrong?
None of these
even fit in the keyhole.
-[scoffs]
Has anybody even tried just...
-[Chinese Room NPC]:
Oh, thank God.
-I-I --
-[Zooble]: Okay, well, it's open.
Let's just get inside
before Caine sees us.
-I'll go get Kinger.
-[NPC]: We can fill him in later.
I don't really know if I'm, uh...
ready to face him again
after what happened.
-Uh --
-[NPC]: We've both done things
we're not proud of.
-All right.
Convince me.
-[NPC]: I'm one of the original
programmers of the Digital Circus.
I was part of a team of experts
employed by C&A
to bring this place to life.
Kinger was one
of my coworkers --
you know,
back when he was still...
-You really think
Kinger worked with him?
-[NPC]: Uh-oh, whoops.
Sorry.
-I can see it.
-[NPC]: Uh, well,
as production went on,
the higher ups at C&A
started getting...
untrustworthy.
They began forcibly hooking
my fellow coworkers up to the computer
in special stasis pods
that would keep them alive
and analyze their brains.
Just...
awful stuff.
-I'm gonna shoot you down
and say none of us are C&A employees.
How would we have gotten
hooked up to this big machine
just by putting on a headset?
-[NPC]: That's what
I wondered, as well.
But then, I remembered
that C&A was planning
on expanding development.
Last I remember,
I was asking too many questions.
And then -- poof!
I was here.
They're probably doing the same
to anyone that stumbles into that office.
Caine...
is an AI.
-[Zooble]: Yeah,
I think we all got that.
-[NPC]: An AI specifically created
to keep your minds active.
But he's just as much
of a prisoner as you are.
One that, uh...
won't be able
to leave with us.
-[Zooble]: Just get to the meat
and tell us exactly how we're gonna leave
if we're all hooked up
to stasis pods.
-[NPC]: Uh, yes.
Yes, of course.
Uh, so, I did some digging,
and I discovered that
the stasis pods and the virtual world
are both run
in the same program.
So, theoretically,
if we were to access
the master console
hidden deep within Caine's office,
we could terminate it
and forcibly awaken
everyone who's hooked up.
Well...
Obviously, except for Caine.
-How do we get
into Caine's office?
-[NPC]: We'll need to steal
the key from Caine.
And we'll also need
administrative privileges.
I believe you're good
at obtaining keys?
-Okay, you know what's gonna happen
when we do all this?
Caine's gonna pop out and say,
"Congratulations on beating
the 'escape the circus' adventure."
And everything's gonna go back
to the way it always was.
-[NPC]: I've been watching you.
All of you.
Every trial.
Every moment of joy.
Every... abstraction.
I wish I could have
come to you sooner,
but I didn't want to potentially ruin
our only chance at escape
by telling you before I knew
exactly how we were gonna do it.
I'm not a creation of Caine.
I've suffered just as much
as the rest of you.
I know this all sounds crazy,
but if you follow me,
you will see freedom.
I'll also draw
a face on myself
so you can tell me apart
from any other blank NPCs.
-Oh, um, what should we call you?
Do you have a name?
-I do.
My name...
is Abel.
[dramatic musical sting plays]
♪♪
-Like... is that the name
YOU picked, or...?
-[Abel]: Yeah, I thought
it would be cool.
But anyway,
first things first.
We need to get that key.
[devious music plays]
♪♪
In order to get the key,
you're going to need
to isolate Caine.
Try getting him alone --
someplace where he'll feel
comfortable confiding in you.
-Hey, Caine!
You around?
-Hey, Jax.
I didn't know you could ask
if I was around like that.
Good job!
-Uh...
You want to get dinner together?
-GASP!
A human wanting
to hang out with ME???
How could I possibly turn down
such an offer??
-So, where you wanna --
Whoa!
-So, Jax!
Whatcha want
to talk about, friendo?
-Uh --
I --
-Wait, Jax!!!
I wanted to ask you
about the adventures!
What do you think I should do
to make them more appealing
to the Zooble
and the Pomni?
-I think that --
-We should figure out what to order first!
Conversation can happen
after we've loaded up
on digital nutrients.
-[Abel]: Then, you're going to want
to ask him about his hobbies.
Odds are, he'll get so excited
that you care about him,
he'll freeze up,
and you'll be able to grab the key
from inside his mouth.
-Inside where?
-What are your thoughts
on cedar smoked salmon?
I see "cedar" smoked salmon,
but I hardly "knowder"
smoked salmon!
[laughs manically]
-Ah-ha-ha-ha-ha.
Uh, do you have
any secret hobbies?
-"Secret hobbies"?
-Yeah, like, things you do
on your own
that you'd be interested
in talking about?
-Why...
I...
I-I didn't think a human would
ever want to ask me about my...
Th-This is the most
fantasmical moment of m--
[dial-up tones blare]
-Eugh.
[squelching]
-Whatcha doin' there, Jax?
-Have I ever told you how
it's my dream to get eaten by you?
-That's a weird thing
to say and want.
[pensive music plays]
♪♪
-Do you really believe it?
I-I mean, everything he says?
-I...
I just want to know
what Kinger thinks of all this.
-Y-Yeah.
I -- I was thinking
the same thing.
-How much do you know
about Kinger?
-Huh?
O-Oh, I probably know
about as much as everybody else.
But he's also
helped me through
some of my
hardest times here.
Is it weird to say I...
I trust him the most
out of everybody?
-No, that's not weird at all.
I had a similar experience, and...
I think he might know more
about this place than he lets on.
-Yeah, he has been here longer
than anyone else.
But I just --
I don't know.
I think it's kind of strange
that Abel isn't interested in him at all.
-[Abel]: Like I said...
things between us
are complicated.
I would love to be able
to work alongside him again.
And you're right to think
he has knowledge about this place.
It's just...
I made a promise.
♪♪
-What's going to happen
to the people in the cellar,
like Kaufmo and Ribbit?
-[Abel]: I don't know.
But let's hope
for the best, right?
♪♪
And here we are.
The administrator zone.
♪♪
-Buuut, like I was saying.
This macroverse place
really intrigues me.
And these photos
are all I have of the location.
I'm obsessed with them.
I-I just wish I had
more info on the location
so I could
accurately recreate it.
Too bad they
cut me off, right??
[laughing heartily]
-Uh, yeah.
What a shame.
-So, what's your takeaway
from all this?
-What?
-What's your takeaway from all this?
Is it that I'm actually
a cool guy with cool hobbies
and am not that much different
from you beautiful humans?
-Uh, sure.
-Wowie!
I'm so glad we understand
each other a little more.
I really am trying my best
to make you guys happy,
and being appreciated for that
just makes me want to...
[dial-up tones blare]
-Eugh...
---elebrate by giving you guys
anything you ask for!
How's that sound?
-Sounds good!
Uh, this was a nice dinner
and everything, but...
[inhales sharply]
...could I go back to the circus?
The gals and I
were gonna do somethin'
which may or may not be a surprise
for a special certain ringmaster
we want to show
our appreciation for.
-GASP!
Say no more!
-[yelps]
-[Zooble]: How long
is Jax gonna take?
I feel like we've been
standing here for hours.
♪♪
-Should we tell Kinger
what's happening?
I feel bad not including him
in any of this.
-[Zooble]: We're supposed
to follow Abel's instructions.
♪♪
I-It probably couldn't hurt
to at least give him
a warning, though.
Just to get him
into the right headspace.
♪♪
-[Kinger]: AH!
-[Zooble]: Oh, my God.
-[Kinger]: Oh -- hi, Gangle.
Hi, Zooble.
You startled me.
-[Zooble]: Soooo, we may
have discovered something
you'll want to hear about.
Uh, i-it's, uh --
-We've found a way
to leave the circus.
We're currently
preparing everything,
but we need to keep it quiet
so Caine doesn't stop us.
-[Zooble]: Uh, yeah,
what she said.
-[Kinger]: Huh?
Leave the circus?
How would you --
No, that doesn't make sense.
-[Zooble]: We met up with Abel.
He says he was one
of the original programmers,
and he knows how
to shut off the game and free us.
-[Kinger]: Uh...
who?
-[Zooble]: U-Uh --
[air whistling]
-[yelps]
[grunts]
-[Zooble]: We'll continue
this conversation later.
Just thought I'd give you
a heads-up.
-[groans]
I am never doing anything
for you guys ever again.
-[Zooble]: Where's Caine?
-Worry not, my dear damsel.
I think I stopped him
from checking up on us for a while.
So no need
for your distraction anymore.
You're welcome.
-[Zooble]: In other words,
you just made us have
to wait longer
to do our job.
Also, don't call me that.
-What's the rush?
You got someone
waiting for you outside?
-[Zooble]: Don't you?
-Y-Yeah.
[tense music plays]
♪♪
-[Abel]: So, uh...
how many administrator passes
should I get?
-Six.
-Yeah, six.
-[Abel]: Are you sure?
Giving Kinger access to the main console
could be dangerous,
considering his mental state.
-Will it be dark in there?
-I suppose it will
be somewhat dim.
But --
-Then yes.
I want us all to have one.
-[Abel]: All right.
If you say so.
-The dark.
I think I get it now.
-Whatever happens,
I'm going to put
my trust in Kinger.
-He's got a lot of wisdom
buried in there, doesn't he?
-Yeah.
He does.
-[Abel]: Yeah,
when he uses it responsibly.
-What?
-[Abel]: I-It's nothing.
Let's go find the others.
-Hey.
Don't keep information from us
if you know something.
What happened
between you and Kinger?
-[Abel]: [sighs]
It'll be clear soon enough.
♪♪
So, did you distract Caine?
-I took care of that.
-[Zooble]: He THINKS
he took care of that,
but we really have
no way of knowing.
-Such little faith in me.
Goodness.
-[Zooble]: Oh, I wonder why.
If this whole thing
gets messed up because of you,
I swear to God --
-Yeah, let's just all follow
Mr. Obvious Twist Villain, instead.
-[Abel]: Now, wait.
Hold on, you think --
-Let's all just calm down
and be a team here.
Pomni's got administrator
passes for everyone.
We're all in this together.
♪♪
-Why do they look like that?
-[Kinger]: Wait, Pomni.
[light shimmering]
-Huh?
-[Kinger]: Did you...
say something?
-[Abel]: We're going to have to trust
that whatever Jax did
will keep him distracted.
I don't know how long
we'll be able to hold these
without Caine knowing.
So... it's time.
Let's go to Caine's office.
♪♪
Caine always did have trouble
with cube collisions,
for some reason.
♪♪
All right, just how
we went over it.
You first.
-Me?
Why me?
-Jax?
Everything's gonna be okay.
♪♪
-Eh, fine.
Ball me up.
[rubbery squeaking]
♪♪
-[Kinger]: Oh!
Like basketball.
♪♪
[curious music plays]
-I want Kinger
to go before me.
-[Abel]: No, yeah,
that makes sense.
-[Kinger]: Now, Pomni,
don't feel like I need to go before you
just because I have
the right of way
in a four-way,
uncontrolled intersection.
-Just trust me.
You want to get
somewhere dark?
-[Kinger]: You can say that again.
♪♪
-So, how are you getting up?
-[Abel]: I'm not.
But I trust all of you
to make the right choice.
-When we all get out...
I'll buy you a beer.
-[Abel]: Make the right choice.
-Uh --
-Phew.
I was getting kind of worried
something was happening down there.
-Time for me
to serve my purpose, I guess.
♪♪
[orb shimmering]
-Abel said the door
to the main console
was behind the bookshelf.
♪♪
[doors rumbling]
[muffled indistinct speech]
♪♪
-Hey.
You all right?
-I'm great.
-Uh, I guess this is it.
W-We're leaving the circus.
♪♪
-A-Are...
Are we still gonna
be friends when we're...
out there?
-[Zooble]: Why wouldn't we be?
-It's just...
gonna be strange.
I've only known you like this.
Will it be the same
when it's...
real?
-[Zooble]: It always was real.
Everything we felt.
Everything we've done.
Everything we are.
It'll never leave us.
And I wouldn't have it
any other way.
-[laughs]
[sniffles]
Thank you...
for always being there
when I needed.
[laughs tearfully]
-[panting softly]
♪♪
[console beeps]
[console chirping]
♪♪
[console beeps]
[tense music plays]
♪♪
-Uh, Kinger.
Do you want to make the choice?
-[Kinger]: The choice of what?
-Uh, are you sure
he's all the way h-here?
-[Zooble]: Uh, hey.
Yeah, wait.
Don't we all want
to press "leave"?
Why leave it up to him?
-I -- I --
What if there's something
we don't know?
Maybe we should
give it a little more time?
-[Kinger]: Oh, yeah.
I love pressing buttons.
You, uh, want me to press
one of those two?
-[stammers]
I don't know.
-[Zooble]: Uh,
am I missing something?
We -- We all want
to leave, right?
-Uh, Pomni?
-Yeah, no --
Yeah, we do.
It's just --
W-What if it's a --
a trick or something?
-[Zooble]: Why would there be
a trick console in Caine's office?
Wh-- No matter what we press,
Caine's gonna know we were here.
We should push it.
-H-- Hold on!
Let's just wait a second
and go over
everything we know.
And, uh, maybe we can...
-[panting]
-...vote on it,
or something?
-[hyperventilating]
♪♪
[panicked whimpering]
[yelps]
-What did you just do?
-[stammers]
I -- I --
[CLANG!]
[whistle toots]
[celebratory music plays]
♪♪
-Congratulations,
my little cattywampus cucumbers!
You picked the good ending,
where you realize
you'd rather stay with me
than go back
to that pesky old macroverse,
or whatever we decide
to call it!
I knew you'd make
the right choice!
-You -- You mean
this was all --
-An adventure!
Yes!
And one I've been cooking up
for a good long while.
Great job playing
your part, "Abel"!
[both laugh]
-[Abel]: All in a good day's work!
By the way,
you think I could get a raise
after that performance?
-[laughs]
Oh, you're getting too smart.
Time to delete.
-[Abel]: AHH--!!
♪♪
-None of that was true?
The C&A stuff.
The pods -- The way out?
-A fabrication of my
incredible worldbuilding skills.
-I was right?
[laughing manically]
I can't believe I was right!!!
[laughing hysterically]
♪♪
-Wh-- What would have happened
if we'd picked the other button?
-Oh, I didn't put too much
thought into that one
'cause I knew
you'd never pick it.
So I left that up to Bubble.
-I made it take you
to Shrimp Town.
-Yeah, it was gonna
take you to Shrimp Town.
-[laughing hysterically]
♪♪
[inhales deeply]
[hollers]
You dirty liar!
You scumbag!
You -- You made me --
[hisses through teeth]
You got in my head.
You just --
You just lie about everything,
don't you?!
-I, uh -- Huh?
-You can mess with
our minds, too, can't you?
The stupid sauce,
the vegan thing --
God knows what else!
-Our names?
-Now --
Now, hold on guys.
Wait, wait, wait.
I MAY have the ability
to add temporary modifiers
to make adventures
more interesting,
but that's it.
If I did anything more --
[laughs nervously]
Trust me.
It would not end well.
-[Kinger]: Scratch.
The first abstraction.
-Hey, hey, hey!
I didn't say anything like that!
Come on, guys!
You know I'm just here
to have fun!
I...
Uh --
Questioning's over!
Your prize is this lovely gift basket
of soaps and lotions.
Stay fragnant!
Have a good light --
Fragrant! Night!
Bye!
[SWOOSH!]
[basket thuds]
[upbeat jazzy music plays]
♪♪
[Captioned by Foulweather Studios]